germanwings.com 2011-06-05

# Data protection at Germanwings

If you have any questions, requests or comments regarding data protection issues, please send an email to our data protection officer at the following address: [datenschutz@germanwings.com](mailto:datenschutz@germanwings.com)

#### Data protection statement

Germanwings considers privacy and personal data protection of paramount importance and we pay special attention to this on our website, [www.germanwings.com](http://www.germanwings.com/).   
Any personal data that is collected while visiting our websites is handled in line with German legislation, the Federal Data Protection Law (BDSG in German), the Telecommunications Media Law (TMG in German), as well as other provisions concerning data protection. At Germanwings we respect your private and personal details.   
To protect your data from any unintentional or deliberate manipulation, loss, deletion or access by unauthorised persons we have in place technical and organisational security measures. As technology advances, we constantly improve these measures.

#### Transferring personal data to third parties

Germanwings does not sell or lend the personal data of its customers or applicants to third parties. The only time we pass on your personal data (including information on your method of payment and flight booking) is to the issuing company of the credit or bankcard you used to pay your booking with. Germanwings reserves the right to pass on personal data to trustworthy third parties carrying out services for you. For example, we pass on data from the Germanwings booking form to the booking form of our partner companies, so that Germanwings customers can book hotels and hire cars and buy travel insurance in a quick and easy way. Beforehand we point out that the data will be passed on and you have to confirm by clicking on “OK”. We only pass on personal data to the authorities in line with valid legal provisions.   
Our staff and suppliers/partners are sworn to confidentiality and data secrecy in line with § 5 of the Federal Data Protection Law (BDSG in German).  
All airlines are legally obliged to disclose the flight and booking details of all passengers to the UK’s customs and border authorities. This data is used exclusively for security-related purposes.

#### Personal data

We need some personal data to be able to deal with your flight booking. When you visit our websites, by default our web servers save the IP address of your internet service provider, the website you used to reach our homepage, the websites you visit at Germanwings, as well as the data and duration of your visit. Germanwings uses cookies to track visitor preferences and adapt our websites accordingly.

The first time you book with Germanwings we ask you to provide specific information, such as your name, address, postal address, telephone number and e-mail address, and then to select a user name and a password. We store this data so that you do not have to re-enter it when you subsequently book online. Alongside this we ask for your payment details, bank details, account number or credit card number every time you make a booking. The flight booking is carried out via SSL (secure socket layer), which transmits the data securely between your web browser and our booking system.

Furthermore, personal data is only stored if it is provided automatically, for instance when you register, fill out a survey, enter a competition or provide it as part of a contract (e.g. a flight).

Data about the flight, passengers, extra services and contact and payment details is also stored beyond the duration of the contract. You can access this data at any time in your profile under “My bookings”.   
To process any online applications, we require some personal details. The first time you apply to Germanwings you will have to enter your name, address, postal address, telephone number and e-mail address on the Germanwings careers page. We will then send you a user name and password, which will allow you to access all the information in Germanwings’ careers section. In order to protect your data you will be asked to change your password after the first time you log on.

#### Right to Retraction

You have the right to obtain your stored data on request and free of charge. Furthermore, you have the right to correct, delete or block incorrect data. Data for accounting and billing purposes will not be affected by cancellation or deletion.

#### Use of Cookies

We use “cookies” (files containing set-up details) in accordance with the provisions of the German Association for the Verification of Distribution of Advertising Media (IVW). These cookies help you to use our products more easily by storing your login data, meaning you do not have to register every time you make a booking. You can also take advantage of our offers without cookies. Most browsers are configured to accept cookies automatically but it is possible to deactivate the storage of cookies or configure your browser to tell you when cookies are sent.

#### Website Tracking

We use cookie-based tracking software to calculate frequency of use and the number of visits. The software, however, does not allow us to collect personal data that would enable us to draw conclusions as to the user’s identity. Germanwings can thus provide statistics on the customer habits of homepage visitors to reputable third-party companies without said statistics containing any personal information that would permit conclusions to be drawn as to the customer’s identity.

#### Your agreement

When you use the Germanwings website, you agree to allow Germanwings to collect information and use it in the manner described above. Due to fast-paced developments in Internet technology we sometimes need to adapt our privacy policy.

We always inform you of these improvements. If you have questions, requests or comments concerning data protection, please send an e-mail to our data protection representative at [datenschutz@germanwings.com](mailto:datenschutz@germanwings.com)

#### Newsletter / Notification Mail

If you have registered for the Germanwings newsletter, you will routinely receive e-mails with news from the airline and current offers. You can unsubscribe to the newsletter at any time by clicking on the corresponding unsubscribe link in the newsletter. To record the responses we use measuring processes customary to the industry, which calculate “click and open” details via hotspots. The data we are provided with is anonymous and aggregate.

#### Links to other websites

Our online offers contain links to other websites that are not covered by this data protection statement. We have no way of ensuring their operators fulfil data protection provisions.
